Pedro Alburqueque

pralburco@gmail.com ■ 754-736-0330 ■ Hollywood, FL 33020

Portfolio: https://prolsu.github.io/portfolio

Summary

Accounting professional with over 6 years of experience. Currently as a Staff Accountant, charged with all payroll related processes including bi-weekly journal entries and monthly accruals. Completed a coding bootcamp from the University of Miami in Spring 2021, and self-teaching new skills in JavaScript, React, and Python.

Skills

Platforms: Windows

 Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, Express, Git, Postman

• **Databases**: MySQL, MongoDB

 Soft Skills: Empathy, problem solving, flexibility/adaptability, curiosity, positivity Accounting: Advanced level of Microsoft Office with emphasis in Excel (pivot tables, vlookup, macros, etc.)

 Accounting Platforms: Data Plus, Paycom, SMS

• Other: Organizational and analytical

Experience

Trump International Beach Resort

Staff Accountant

Sunny Isles Beach, FL December 2020 - Present

- Responsible for the bi-weekly payroll process covering over 250 employees
- Prepare Excel reports to distribute tips and gratuities, bonuses, incentives, and commissions
- Manage and maintain PTO balances, accruals, and rollovers per pay period
- Add garnishments according to court orders and maintain shared records with HR department
- In charge of bi-weekly payroll journal entries, monthly payroll accruals and reversals
- Prepare labor-to-budget reports and present labor review meetings to managers and directors
- Responsible of the general cashier tasks, including daily cash deposits and in-house bank audits
- Process monthly travel agent commission report and issue payments accordingly
- Prepare monthly shared expenses for the property's association company

Trump International Beach Resort

Accounts Payables/Accounting Generalist

Sunny Isles Beach, FL December 2014 - December 2020

- Entered large volumes of invoices and credit memos and reconciled against PO's daily
- Processed weekly check runs and off-cycle/manual checks with great attention to details
- Established and maintained relationships with new and existing vendors
- Ensured invoices and payroll manual checks were paid on time following stablished company policies
- Resolved vendor inquiries and payment discrepancies
- Routed incoming invoices to the appropriate parties within the organization for approvals
- Reconciled vendor statements and researched discrepancies

Charged with the accounts payable month end close processes

Ark Restaurants

Hollywood, FL

Food Court Manager

January 2009 – December 2014

- Managed the night and overnight staff in a restaurant of 25+ team members
- Assisted the general manager and executive chef with scheduling and purchase orders
- Delegated tasks, enforced company procedures and policies, and provided guidance and training
- Responded to guest complaints and resolved them in order to ensure the guest will return
- Ensured profitability of restaurant operations by working within cost of goods and labor cost
- Ensured all restaurant paperwork is completed on a timely basis and accurately
- Trained new team members in our POS platforms and cash handling procedures
- Maintained required staff based on business levels and revenue forecast nightly

Education

UNIVERSITY OF MIAMI

March 2021

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate

Languages

English & Spanish